MATTHEW D. STALEY

DILIGENT. INNOVATIVE. PERCEPTIVE.

4101 Lincoln Way Apt. 206, San Francisco CA, 94122 (949)293-7800 staley.d.matthew@gmail.com

CAREER SUMMARY

I have been studying and teaching mathematics for the last ten years. My background is rooted in functional analysis, linear algebra, optimization and statistics. During the last two years in grad school, I developed an interest for computer science and data analytics. I have done small projects on my own and through my academic experience; writing code in Python and R. Currently, I am studying how to code more proficiently in Python, SQL, Java and HTML.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Retained an average teaching evaluation score of 4/5 at SFSU, with 9 classes over a 2 year period.
- Supervised and tested SFSU's contemporary online homework system, "Revitalizing Algebra".
- Attained Master of Arts in Mathematics at SFSU, with a cumulative GPA of 3.6.
- Sustained Lyft driver rating of 4.94/5 on 200 rides to date, with a clean driving record and no accidents.
- Volunteered at Project Open Hand in San Francisco.
- Authored student solution manuals for calculus courses at Saddleback Community College.
- Established the Supplemental Instruction program at Saddleback Community College.
- Mentored and trained new tutors at Saddleback Community College.
- Boosted students' math scores by multiple letter grades.
- Received a Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics at UC Berkeley, with a cumulative GPA of 3.34.
- Completed Hindi language introduction course while studying abroad in New Delhi, India.
- Recognized jazz musician.

PROJECTS: MATTHEWDSTALEY.GITHUB.IO

- "Models of Hyperbolic Geometry" Expository paper fulfilling the MA requirements at SFSU.
- "Hierarchical Models, Model Fitting and Inference for GLMMs" A research project in categorical data analysis.
- "Mushrooms of Madagascar" data visualization of GPS data using R.
- Project Euler A sample of coded solutions in Python.
- Grade estimator and GPS calculator for SFSU students. (In Progress)

Work History

- Lyft (2014- Present) Personal Driver
 - · Accommodated passengers of all backgrounds and needs.
 - · Courteous, considerate, safe and professional.
 - · Self-directed and self-motivated.
- SFSU (2013-2015) Graduate Teaching Assistant
 - · Facilitated active learning environments from algebra through calculus.
 - · Formulated lectures, homework and quizzes.
 - · Graded and assessed student work.
- Saddleback Community College, CA (2011-2013) Tutor and Teaching Assistant
 - \cdot Mentored students in Statistics, Trigonometry and Multivariable Calculus.
- UC Berkeley (2008-2010) Math Tutor
 - · Tutored for all varieties of math classes at the Student Learning Center.
 - · Designed study aide materials and legitimized study groups.

EDUCATION

- San Francisco State University: Master of Arts Mathematics, 2015
- University of California, Berkeley: Bachelor of Arts Mathematics, 2011
- University of Delhi, India: Study Abroad January to May 2011
- Saddleback Community College: Associates Degree Mathematics, 2008